THANAKON SUANGSAWANG

(นายธนกร ทรวงแสวง)

25/71 SOI.INTAMARA2

SAMSEN-NAI PAYATHAI

BANGKOK 10400

081-668-8755

THANAKON@OUTLOOK.COM

DATE OF BIRTH: 31 AUGUST 1981

DATE OF AVAILABILITY: IMMEDIATELY

Objective: I am looking for a position as a Senior System Analyst or Solution/IT Architect in the organization where I can utilize my skills at designing the solutions.

Summary:

12 years of experience in international IT consulting firms. Providing consultancy services to clients mostly in Banking and Telco industries. Lead team in a variety of environments. Hands-on experience in integration team leader, system analyst, business analyst with project management skill, strong technical background, coupled with a CISA (Certified Information System Auditor) certification.

Professional Experience -

IBM(Thailand) Co. Ltd

Advisory IT Specialst, April 2011 – March 2016

Client: Kasikorn Bank (KBank)

Project Overview: Core banking replacement project involving more than 300 legacies application with highly complex environment and complex requirement.

Role: Senior System Analyst / Senior Business Analyst / Integration Team Leader

Duration: April 2011 – February 2016

Job details:

- Designed the integration API/Protocol for online transaction processing between new core banking and existing legacies applications in Mainframe.
- Designed the integration API for batch processing.
- Managed 20 applications under my portfolio. Control the quality of the deliverables, ensure the completeness and consistence of the deliverable. Mitigate the risk through the project management.
- Assist in the gathering of customer requirements, including functional and nonfunctional requirements of the applications.
- Coordinate with application teams to provide the impact analysis on related solution including provide support for the functional/integration workshop, track and follow-up the pre-requisite documents/information as required to be submitted for the workshop
- Assist the application business analyst in creating detailed requirements that specify the technical architecture of the system
- Review application requirements for reasonability and conformance to project constraints and the Bank's standards and promote compliance with established architectures.
- Assist application teams in describing the functionality of the IT system, including designing the interactions between a system's components, defining the interfaces provided by components, and documenting the dynamic behavior of a system as expressed by
- Work with vendors and KBank and in the development of multi-vendor solutions.
- Tailor the development methodology to support specific tools, infrastructure and procedures for the targeted development environment
- Participate in other value-added operational processes such as project planning, staffing, testing, and quality assurance
- Primary point of contact to ensure the quality of deliverables.
- Manage change requests those related to the interface lines under my portfolio.

Avanade(Thailand) Co. Ltd Solution Consultant, August 2004 – December 2010

Project Name: NCCA-DCARE

Client: DTAC

Client Overview: Major mobile operator **Period:** February 2009 – December 2010

Project Overview: NCCA: DCARE is a web portal that provides DTAC's users access to

knowledgebase for information related to customer services (call center), collaboration and access to online applications from a single point of access. In addition, NCCA:DCARE provides Web Content Management functionality for Content Authoring team to create web contents that can be accessed from within the portal.

Role: Team Leader

Job details: This project is to upgrade the system from Microsoft CMS Server and Microsoft SharePoint Portal Server 2002 to Microsoft Office SharePoint Server 2007, My responsibilities includes requirement gathering , solution design , man day estimation , develop functional specification, detailed design, test script, coach team.

Technical solution: Microsoft SharePoint 2007, C#.NET, Web Services.

Project Name: POS-BLAND

Client: PROVINCIAL ELECTRICITY AUTORITY (PEA)

Period: Dec 2008 – Feb 2009

Project Overview: POS-BLAN is a smart-client application that designed to cater for bill payment for PEA. This application needs to deploy country wide with more than 1,200 clients connect to central server. Team has encounter performance issue. I was engaged to help in performance testing and SOL tuning.

Role: Solution Consultant – Performance Test and SQL Tuning

Job details: Prepare test scenario, test script, performs performance test using Visual Studio 2005,

and SQL tuning.

Technical solution: .NET Smart Client, C#.NET, Web Services, SQL Server 2005

Project Name: Contact Center System **Client:** Krung Thai Credit Card - KTC

Client Overview: Krung Thai Card Public Company Limited (KTC) is a leading consumer finance

provider in Thailand.

Period: September 2007 – November 2008

Project Overview: KTC needs to develop and expand to complete contact center, which can able to deliver 'One Stop' services to customers by efficient controlled operation. And reporting system. Project is to deliver the integrated front and back end Contact Center System, which includes the telephony system and agent's application.

Role: Solution consultant – Integration Lead

Job details: The project is to deliver Call Center System (Microsoft CRM) as a frontend application which is need to integration with legacy backend systems, I was in the position of integration lead with 2 team member in my supervision, my job is to help get the requirement and design the interface of integration between Microsoft CRM and backend systems, including MSMQ, Web Service and Flat file integration, All of this system connected using EAI (BizTalk 2006). Interface specification is also under my responsibility.

Technical solution: Microsoft CRM, BizTalk 2006.

Project: File Transform Gateway

Client: Krung Thai Computer Service (KCS)

Client Overview: KCS is established to provide high quality IT-based products services to KTB and

other subsidiaries.

Period: April 2007 – August 2007

Project Overview: The File Transform Gateway solution utilizes Microsoft BizTalk server as the integration platform. BizTalk's messaging component is used to perform data format translation. BizTalk's orchestration component is used to perform the actual business process manage and automation works. The orchestration component handles data validation and required business rules. The project was completed over a period of 5 month.

Role: Solution Consultant – Team Lead

Job details: The file transform gateway solution implement using Microsoft BizTalk Server 2006 shall provide services to facilitate communication between front-end and backend system using flat file and web service with logic to transform data format. I was team lead for this project with 4 team members under my supervision. Functional specifications, detailed design, Test case, Operation manual are documents I have developed for this project.

Technical solution: Microsoft BizTalk Server 2006, Microsoft SQL Server 2000, C#.NET, Web

Services

Project Name: IT Master Plan

Client: Thailand Post

Client Overview: Thailand post is the biggest post offices in Thailand with more than 1,160 branches operate mail delivery as core service with additional lines of business including money transfer, bill payment, etc.

Period: June 2006 – March 2007

Project Overview: Assessment of Existing IT Infrastructure/Application, Developing IT Strategy for Thailand Post, Requirements gathering and design overall system, Deliver TOR to select required vendor.

Role: IT Consultant

Job details: To do the assessment of existing IT solutions in Thailand Post. And develop IT master plans for the next 5 years and also develop TOR (Terms of Reference) for the new POS system.

Project Name: NewCase

Client: International SOS (ISOS), Singapore

Client Overview: The International SOS is a global medical assistance company with additional

lines of business including specialty services.

Period: Jan 2006 – May 2006

Project Overview: The NewCase project is to be the client's core service delivery that contains key assistance and incident related information. This system is intended to facilitate their assistance team in delivering service to our clients 'end-to-end' from the point of first call to the production of client service invoice and provide integration to email, fax, scanning and the ability to replicate and share information across multiple medical centers globally.

Role: I was a part of the development team. Developed customizable components for several areas of the application. This included, an engine catering to a multi-level question and answer section and the automation of MS Word Find and Replace within the application.

Technical solution: MS .NET (C# Sharp), SQL Server 2000

Project Name: Studio Framework

Client: Government Investment of Singapore , Singapore

Client Overview: The Customer is a global investment management company established in 1981 to manage Singapore's foreign reserves and invests internationally in equities, fixed income, money market instruments, real estate and special investments.

Period: June 2005 – December 2005

Project Overview: The objective of Studio Framework is to create a Framework to provide common functionality for other 3 projects. The common functionality including copy page function, save search criteria, deletes SharePoint page.

Role: My primary role was as a developer on this project. To do the detailed design, functional specification. Test script and to develop the solution.

Technical solution: Microsoft SQL Server 2000, VB.NET, User control, SharePoint Portal Server

Project Name : CDS SCM KPI Web Report System **Client Overview :** Robinson Information Service

Project Overview: The objective of CDS SCM KPI Web Report System project is to create a KPI web report system for the Client to measure performance of vendors by analyzing sales and stock information of itemized consignment products sold in various department stores and sub departments across different geographical locations.

Period: October 2004 – April 2005

Role: My primary role was as a developer on this project. To created and modified Store procedure for reporting service and prepared data for testing during UAT and performance tests.

Technical solution: Microsoft SQL Server 7.0, Active Server Pages, DTS, Microsoft Web Application Stress Tool(ACT).

Internet Thailand Co Ltd.

Developer, October 2003 - September 2004

- Requirement gathering, analysis, design, develop web site Thai.net
- System support.
- Technical solution: .Net , ASP , Microsoft SQL

Education -

2010: Master Degree from King Mongkut's University of Technology Thonburi M.Sc. (Information Technology)

2003: Bachelor Degree from Silpakorn University, B.Sc. (Computer Science)

1999: High School, Demonstration School of Rajjaphat Pra Nakorn Si Ayutthaya University

Technical Skills =

- Microsoft SharePoint Portal Server 2007 / 2010
- C#.Net
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Microsoft Dynamic AX
- Oracle DB
- Mainframe Z/OS

- Microsoft BizTalk Server
- VB.Net
- Web Services
- Cloud Foundation
- Java

Certification & Training =

- Certified Information System Auditor (CISA)
- Microsoft BizTalk
- Microsoft Project Server

- Microsoft SharePoint Portal Server
- Microsoft SQL